<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:21:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I have long advocated that the Euro should become a parallel currency and not a substitute currency in the various states in Europe.  I have also argued long and hard for a confederation of states in Europe and not a headlong rush toward a Federated Europe, a plan so beloved of the mandarins in Europe.  Opinion pieces as set out below were simply unheard of a while back, but now are becoming more prevalent and I am now interested to understand when we shall see a tipping point away from the current consensus over the EU.  My thoughts are that the negotiations that are gathering momentum as Great Britain sets up its new relationship with the EU could be the catalyst for the tipping point, but it’s still too early to make a definitive prediction.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/5d637555-ce78-4867-a76d-22851bb934ea/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5d637555-ce78-4867-a76d-22851bb934ea</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:20:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Harry StephanSenior Lecturer</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/dr-harry-stephansenior-lecturer/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9673b1df-37fa-4043-98d7-a89fad47fe19</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:11:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Which Way Europe?  Interpreting the Principle of Subsidiarity.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Which Way Europe?  Interpreting the Principle of Subsidiarity.</h1><p>The United Kingdom goes to the Polls on June 23rd 2016, more divided than ever over its roll within the European Union.  David Cameron has argued for Great Britain to remain within the EU after gaining ‘special status’ within the 28-nation bloc.  With great fanfare, Cameron has argued that Great Britain should be able to opt out of the EU’s founding ambition to forge an ‘ever closer union’ of the peoples of Europe. It will not be drawn into further political integration in a ‘formal, legally binding and irreversible way.’ Essentially Cameron is arguing for greater powers for national parliaments to block EU legislation.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/which-way-europe-interpreting-the-principle-of-subsidiarit/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d000f173-c4b4-4578-a69b-c8a829bdd652</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:10:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nationalism and Identity:  Will Brexit best Brussels? ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Nationalism and Identity:  Will Brexit best Brussels? </h1><p>Previously I wrote on nationalism, introducing Aristotle’s arguments in theNicomachean Ethics.I now want to unpack the argument of Boris Johnson, the Mayor of London, who spoke on March 6th 2016 at Dartford in the United Kingdom and then later on the BBC’s Andrew Marr Show.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/nationalism-and-identity-will-brexit-best-brussels/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">27f08229-25ca-4a2b-8bba-c2521086d99a</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:10:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The European Union Today:  The Logical Limits of Functionalism]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The European Union Today:  The Logical Limits of Functionalism</h1><p>Joseph Stiglitz, writing the foreword to Karl Polanyi’s classic book describing the great transformation of European civilization from the preindustrial world to the era of industrialization, argues forcefully that the issues and perspectives Polanyi raises have not lost their salience.  Among Polanyi’s central theses are the ideas that self-regulating markets never work; their deficiencies are so great that government intervention becomes absolutely necessary.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/the-european-union-today-the-logical-limits-of-functionali/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">006ea339-b7a6-4d29-9387-1bf4c2aa4f52</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:09:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unequal Exchange on an Ebbing Tide]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Unequal Exchange on an Ebbing Tide</h1><p>In 1963, to combat criticism against a dam project he was inaugurating, President John F. Kennedy argued that a ‘Rising Tide lifts all boats’.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/unequal-exchange-on-an-ebbing-tide/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4d8fb873-95eb-49c1-b8fd-541acc9a78b2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:09:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Will Today’s Insanity once again Trump the International Financial System?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Will Today’s Insanity once again Trump the International Financial System?</h1><p>With Europe officially entering a deflationary moment at the end of February, issues surrounding austerity and the nature of deflation on the international economic system are once more an interesting topic of discussion.  How, you may ask, are these issues related to the key paradigms that underpinned Bretton Woods?</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/will-todays-insanity-once-again-trump-the-international-fin/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bc027da3-44e8-4b2a-9bd5-5765879e4887</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:09:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Backstabbing Boris, Brexit, and the implications for HST]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Backstabbing Boris, Brexit, and the implications for HST</h1><p>Since I decided on a curriculum for this class, Boris Johnson has decided to support Brexit.  His decision will make a huge impact on this course, as we shall have to argue over the implications of the decision on whether Great Britain stays or leaves through our theoretical lenses on the international political system, or if you will, the international political economy. Currently the polls are showing that the ‘in’ and ‘out’ campaigns are neck and neck and this has already impacted the Pound Sterling, which is losing ground against the Dollar, the Euro and the Swiss Franc rather smartly.  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/backstabbing-boris-brexit-and-the-implications-for-hst/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a368358e-0b05-45e1-80a8-44dbfcc711fe</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:09:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Iran Nuclear Deal]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Iran Nuclear Deal</h1><p>Over the past months, I have focused attention on two core issues: The Greek debt crisis, which has dogged the European Union for years, and the Nuclear Deal with Iran, which has polarized politics in the United States.  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/iran-nuclear-deal/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ef559904-14f8-40f0-87c1-a90716c8ab09</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:08:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One Minute to Midnight: Greece is Turning in the Wind]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>One Minute to Midnight: Greece is Turning in the Wind</h1><p>To my mind, Greece hit its 11th hour some time ago.  In fact I first started to make inquiries about Greek debt and posted on this subject in February 2013. I believe that the financial dilemma that developed in Greece epitomizes the failure of the European Union's mandarins to recognize that political solutions and political institutions are always necessary to run civil society.  Relying on an incorrect economic model through the ECB to correct fiscal imbalances is near to impossible, and the past two years have certainly proved this notion correct. Now that Greece is on the very edge, opinion makers are taking time out of their own schedules to pass comment.  Joseph Stiglitz, who is always worth a read, now has his say, and he certainly makes a strong argument below. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/one-minute-to-midnight-greece-is-turning-in-the-wind/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8be82569-beb0-4b5e-b2c1-ccf6690893e7</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 04:07:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>