<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:52:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POL 5032 Week V]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>POL 5032 Week V</h1>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/pol-5032-week-v/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9e2fc8b0-ed02-434a-9570-ec73b69cdcda</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:52:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POl 5032 Week IV]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>POl 5032 Week IV</h1>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/pol-5032-week-iv/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">93a4ca13-df20-4dd5-86fe-f60412fb3cb7</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:52:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POL 5032  Week III]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>POL 5032  Week III</h1><p>What are the key premises that underpin GATT and now the WTO?  Are multi-lateral trade agreements still applicable within the world trading regime, and if not why not?</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/pol-5032-week-iii/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">83e07bdb-f3d2-45e7-a103-f34adfc0dcca</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:52:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POl 5032 Week II]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>POl 5032 Week II</h1><p>Can you explain Susan Strange’s Finance structure in terms of the Bretton Woods institutions?  What are the fundamental changes that have occurred within the financial structure since WWII and how does the financial structure play out within the international financial system today?</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/pol-5032-week-ii/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">76996440-606a-44a4-aab8-13278b34cfb8</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:51:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[POL 5032]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>POL 5032</h1><p>A new year, a new beginning in the graduate school. This year we have to answer nine questions and I want to address each one of them each week to see whether I can tease out some semblance of continuity.  And so:</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/pol-5032/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">36e19cae-e638-48bb-bac5-69b8fd86d432</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:51:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Greece Again]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Greece Again</h1><p>WIll the Greek government vote a budget that crushes the Greeks yet again?  Greece is predicted to fall short at Euro 2.5-billion this year, so cuts have to be made.  Yet the Greek government is hanging on with a margin of just four seats, and the Greeks are no longer willing to make any more sacrifices on the alter of EU austerity.  If a budget does pass that includes the required cuts, expect massive riots. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/greece-again/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b3a1f269-a760-4749-a972-5d7f41d8dbdf</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:51:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Answering the Mail]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Answering the Mail</h1><p>How much attention do you feel Russia deserves in considerations about the EU's future? Russia seems at once a divisive factor, with regard to energy policy, and a unifying factor, due to shared suspicion. Until the EU can come up with a common energy policy, Russia is able to divide and rule in this regard. Germany and Russia are linked directly now via Nordstream. I wonder how this will play out in future with regard to Britain and US antipathy towards Russia and Germany's compromised position.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/answering-the-mail/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bb8d624c-a94b-4076-b9f3-54d78d0ef116</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:50:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A false Start]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>A false Start</h1><p>Well here we are back in South Africa after a wonderful trip to Europe where I had the good fortune to meet with Professor Kuehnhardt, a noted authority on the European Union.  With the best will in the world, I set out to write on my arguments and research in Europe only to find that I had to undergo an operation.  Now in recovery and writing is postponed.  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/a-false-start/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e8485829-2fed-4cba-9e95-a130f296ee5a</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:50:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four Issues]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Four Issues</h1><p>​This week I feel that I have solved three of four concerns that I have been wrestling with on the future of the European Union.  The first turned on legal issues that have been addressed by the German Courts.  Appears that the German Courts are moving in a manner that allows for more space to address the future direction of the EU and where we shall see the locus of power in the future.  It would appear that the US model of a Federal system is no longer considered the only model and the courts are going to influence the debate on the EU going forward.  A treatment on the legal future of the EU is thus absolutely necessary.  Second, when looking at Balassa, Haas, Hettne et al, the notion of an economic solution was implicit in the way a region developed.  But now I am not so sure.  These theories have to be reworked and possibly Robert Mundell's work, despite its flaws, on Optimum Currency Areas may provide the necessary direction I am looking for to rework the economic arguments on the nature of the EU going forward. Then third, I have found very interesting material on European culture that is underpinned by nationalism and the relationship of the member states to the EU.   The political leverage, either for convergence or devolution is quite fascinating, and takes me to my core problem right now.   This problem turns on the nature of political unrest within Europe and where this may lead.  There is no doubt in my mind that poor economic performance is leading to solid gains in Greece by the radical right, and we should see more of this within those  states that also begin experiencing economic decline.  Will this change dissipate if Europe can rebound?  Is the link real?    Is the economic structure within the EU governing political change, or can we flip the argument and maintain that political structures are causing the economic malaise on the periphery?  I simply don't know how to formulate the connection.  My concern now is that France will soon become the sick man of Europe.  To my mind, this will result from a problem of France's competitiveness within the Euro area.  Thus it appears that we shall witness more problems in Europe due to the straightjacket maintained by the single currency.  Will France balk and jump away or stay the course? How will this effect the political trajectory towards Balassa's final solution of a single federated Europe? The alternative, France buys into Cameron's notions of political and economic devolution. Something will have to give.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/four-issues/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">53e3540a-458e-47af-abd0-fd3ea2bf3f62</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:50:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Theories of Regionalism]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Theories of Regionalism</h1><p>Thursdays, as always, involve graduate students.  Such a pleasure setting out arguments, but on this Thursday we debated the nature of regionalism in the East African Community, and especially the work of Eathan B. Kapstein.  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/new-theories-of-regionalism/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b04bac28-71de-4866-81af-c13cda8fd56e</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:49:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>