<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:51:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Answering the Mail]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Answering the Mail</h1><p>How much attention do you feel Russia deserves in considerations about the EU's future? Russia seems at once a divisive factor, with regard to energy policy, and a unifying factor, due to shared suspicion. Until the EU can come up with a common energy policy, Russia is able to divide and rule in this regard. Germany and Russia are linked directly now via Nordstream. I wonder how this will play out in future with regard to Britain and US antipathy towards Russia and Germany's compromised position.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/answering-the-mail/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bb8d624c-a94b-4076-b9f3-54d78d0ef116</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:50:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A false Start]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>A false Start</h1><p>Well here we are back in South Africa after a wonderful trip to Europe where I had the good fortune to meet with Professor Kuehnhardt, a noted authority on the European Union.  With the best will in the world, I set out to write on my arguments and research in Europe only to find that I had to undergo an operation.  Now in recovery and writing is postponed.  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/a-false-start/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e8485829-2fed-4cba-9e95-a130f296ee5a</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:50:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Four Issues]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Four Issues</h1><p>​This week I feel that I have solved three of four concerns that I have been wrestling with on the future of the European Union.  The first turned on legal issues that have been addressed by the German Courts.  Appears that the German Courts are moving in a manner that allows for more space to address the future direction of the EU and where we shall see the locus of power in the future.  It would appear that the US model of a Federal system is no longer considered the only model and the courts are going to influence the debate on the EU going forward.  A treatment on the legal future of the EU is thus absolutely necessary.  Second, when looking at Balassa, Haas, Hettne et al, the notion of an economic solution was implicit in the way a region developed.  But now I am not so sure.  These theories have to be reworked and possibly Robert Mundell's work, despite its flaws, on Optimum Currency Areas may provide the necessary direction I am looking for to rework the economic arguments on the nature of the EU going forward. Then third, I have found very interesting material on European culture that is underpinned by nationalism and the relationship of the member states to the EU.   The political leverage, either for convergence or devolution is quite fascinating, and takes me to my core problem right now.   This problem turns on the nature of political unrest within Europe and where this may lead.  There is no doubt in my mind that poor economic performance is leading to solid gains in Greece by the radical right, and we should see more of this within those  states that also begin experiencing economic decline.  Will this change dissipate if Europe can rebound?  Is the link real?    Is the economic structure within the EU governing political change, or can we flip the argument and maintain that political structures are causing the economic malaise on the periphery?  I simply don't know how to formulate the connection.  My concern now is that France will soon become the sick man of Europe.  To my mind, this will result from a problem of France's competitiveness within the Euro area.  Thus it appears that we shall witness more problems in Europe due to the straightjacket maintained by the single currency.  Will France balk and jump away or stay the course? How will this effect the political trajectory towards Balassa's final solution of a single federated Europe? The alternative, France buys into Cameron's notions of political and economic devolution. Something will have to give.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/four-issues/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">53e3540a-458e-47af-abd0-fd3ea2bf3f62</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:50:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Theories of Regionalism]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Theories of Regionalism</h1><p>Thursdays, as always, involve graduate students.  Such a pleasure setting out arguments, but on this Thursday we debated the nature of regionalism in the East African Community, and especially the work of Eathan B. Kapstein.  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/new-theories-of-regionalism/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b04bac28-71de-4866-81af-c13cda8fd56e</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:49:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In the modern era, Europe provides easily the most famous and most successful example of regionalism at work. Early theories of regionalism were almost entirely Euro-centric, and many of the ideas, which first emerged in response to the European experience are still influential today. In particular, Haas’s concept of functional spillover represents a watershed in the development of the literature, and as we will later argue, is still of central importance today.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/a7562fec-c31b-4dda-8d27-c6d7a9c37e7c/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a7562fec-c31b-4dda-8d27-c6d7a9c37e7c</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:49:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Two Households]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Two Households</h1><p>Two households, both alike in dignity………</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/two-households/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">269f8263-8b59-49da-897c-97a3516082fc</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:48:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Commentary]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Commentary</h1><p>My thanks to all of you who have commented on my recent musings.  Appears that you all prefer to write directly to me, so this defeats the idea of a conversation.  Ah well.  What is fast becoming apparent is that you are split into two camps:  one which believes that Euroland does not have a reverse gear and thus will continue down the path to a closer union; and the other, which believes in some form of breakup.  </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/commentary/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">712f6c98-a176-4af2-8c29-cecfd99caa31</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:48:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The European Union - New Thoughts]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The European Union - New Thoughts</h1><p>When I last wrote about the problems of the European Union and their implications for a new book, my mind was focused on the debate between economics and politics.  I was still deeply immersed and influenced by the arguments that were advanced by Ernst Haas on neo-functionalism and the federalists within Europe.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/the-european-union-new-thoughts/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c61ea726-ee38-4145-9584-7c2008c0d1ee</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:47:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>South African Journal of International Affairs  Vol. 19:3. 2012. PP. 409-411. ​</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/5fb0f9d5-e98b-4650-8f39-ffc3d40b05cd/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5fb0f9d5-e98b-4650-8f39-ffc3d40b05cd</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:46:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Scale of Greek Debt]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Scale of Greek Debt</h1><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/4dad65e09e6471f13c386912d656bade968d17a5.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/the-scale-of-greek-debt/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b791f3aa-f95d-482b-b011-13c13f28dfa2</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:45:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>