<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Dr. Harry Stephan]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:35:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thoughts on the book's spine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Thoughts on the book's spine</h1><p>The European Union:  50 Years After the Elysee Treaty</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/thoughts-on-the-books-spine/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">192115ad-a889-483b-ac6a-dd677bc4a93d</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:35:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The EU]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The EU</h1><p>What are the origins of European integration, and how far back in time do we need to travel to pick up these first stirrings. Do we have to at all?   I'd like to begin this conversation by taking us back to the Congress of Vienna as this will allow a theoretical discussion on what motivated the nation states at the time to develop a 'Concert of Europe'  What was the origin of the idea of the balance of power?  How did European leaders apply its principles in actual practice?  If we fast forward to today, can we argue whether the notion of a balance of power still applies within the European region?  Is the balance now a balance based on financial muscle and do the nation states of Europe feel it necessary to balance against Germany's new-found power?  Is the EU now centralized sufficiently to prevent the states on the margins from spinning away? Does the very economic union created by the EU encourage the latent nationalism that simmers below the surface in Catalonia and Scotland? Will the Lega Nord  fianlly win independece for the North from the South in Italy?  To my mind, any discussion on concepts such as the balance of power must include a treatment on nationalism and all its ramifications.  This will be the point of departure for this book. </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/the-eu/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2a7e4597-b543-4337-9d1f-3d32409835fc</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:34:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The European Union:  Will the Elysee Treaty Hold for another 50 Years?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The European Union:  Will the Elysee Treaty Hold for another 50 Years?</h1><p>Nationalism as a concept lost ground in the recent past as the idea of the European Union took hold.  But as we probe the crisis of the EU in the 21st Century, can we honestly argue that nationalism is a dead issue?  In the period following the Great Depression we witnessed the rise of the Iron Guard in Romania, the Falangist movement  in Spain and Fascism under Benito Mussolini in Italy. What of Golden Dawn in Greece today, and can we argue with certainty that populists and parties of the right will not dominate politics in Europe again? </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/dr-harry-stephan/the-european-union-will-the-elysee-treaty-hold-for-another/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">408637ae-05a3-4a27-845d-afda8fbdc18b</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 03:35:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>